[Music]
so we're going to do
another ben and jerry's flavor this one
is salted caramel brownie but the topped
version
and with joe biden now the president of
the united states he's a big ice cream
fan so at some point we'll do something
with that but uh we'll get onto this one
now
so what is the salted caramel
brownie tops i mean it's a vanilla ice
cream with salted caramel swirl brownie
chunks
the little chocolate chunks as well but
they're ampersand shaped we don't have
that
so we're gonna use a different one
that's all then topped
with a milk chocolate layer on top
and that's it so nice easy one hopefully
to make
let's just crack on and do it so we're
going to start with making the little
chocolate shapes
so for that we're going to use the
chocolate carrots that we use in a lot
of our videos you can use whatever
chocolate you like dark chocolate i mean
something around the 50 to 70 mark would
be
ideal for this but whatever you got is
absolutely fine
so we're going to make those up now and
get them in the mold
[Music]
so to make the brownies put your butter
and chocolate in the microwave bowl
once that's melted in the microwave add
your sugar
and your three eggs and then give it a
really good stir you want to make sure
that those eggs and sugar are
incorporated well
into that mix that's going to be the
basis of how good your brownies are
then you're going to need a much bigger
bowl than i used in that put your
flour your baking powder and your salt
along with three tablespoons of high
quality cocoa
add in your brownie batter and then
again give that a really good stir
make sure you don't have a flour
explosion everywhere once your batter is
ready
take it out and put it in a lined baking
pan this is an 8x8 but just use whatever
you got
once it's done pop it in the oven 170
for 30 minutes and you're good to go
so for the caramel sauce we actually had
some of this leftover from
our fish food ice cream so i'm not gonna
make a salted caramel sauce when i've
got that there's no point wasting
good caramel sauce so i'm sure ben and
jerry's are gonna
really hate me for using jude sauce in
the ice cream but
it is what it is so to make this ben and
jerry's ice cream we're going to use
one of the recipes from that book i'll
put a picture
on b-roll just in case you didn't see
this one and we're going to use the
sweet cream base number one
now on this it's a very simple recipe
and i'm absolutely positive that they
don't use this but any of their ice
creams because they'll use
some mass-produced heavily stabilized
maybe a non-cooked base it's quite
possibly a non-cooked base
but the importance is the stabilizer
there's lots of different types of
stabilizer out there from
different gums to powders to eggs and
custards lots of kind of things what
difference do they do they're all
slightly different but essentially
they'll create a
softer ice cream that lasts better or
longer in
the freezer if you don't put a
stabilizer in of some kind
or you or you don't use enough sugar in
your ice cream it will freeze like a
brick
and you'll have to leave it for about
15-20 minutes before you can eat it and
don't want one side you want to take the
ice cream
out the freezer dig in and eat the whole
tub
maybe that's just me this ice cream is
really simple to make first you're gonna
put
your eggs into the bowl and then slowly
combine the sugar
whisking really really well make sure
that sugar is incorporated
then add your milk and cream giving that
a final whisk make sure it's all
combined
and then lastly is your vanilla extract
you can use vanilla pods if you like but
we're going to use
the nice nielsen mason vanilla extract
good quality on
once that's all made then just get it in
your ice cream maker
and it will take about 20 to 30 minutes
depending on what one you've got
once it's ready we'll come back to you
see you in 30.
[Music]
right so what we're going to do is load
the tub up we're going to layer in the
brownies
and the chocolate and then finally swirl
in
some nice sauce from that point we'll
put it in the freezer for
about half an hour just to make the
icing go off then we'll take it back out
and do the chocolate top
so the final part of this ice cream is
the chocolate top the topped
part of it but we're going to make it
with
a crackle top type of chocolate so the
stuff that you put on top of ice cream
and it goes hard you correct your spoon
through it
we've stuffed it it's been around for
donkey's years almost as long as i have
so to do that we're going to use coconut
oil and
just our 70 chocolate
put one teaspoon of coconut oil into 100
grams of chocolate put it in the
microwave
for however long it takes 30 seconds
something like that but make sure you
check it
stir it well and then what we're going
to do now is put it straight on top
of the ice cream layer onto the ice
cream nice and quick because you want to
get it straight back into the freezer
and leave it in there for at least a
couple of hours and that's all there is
to it
we'll come back to you in probably 12
hours next day tomorrow something like
that
and we'll show you what the result is
so it's the next day 24 hours later give
or take
and this has been in the freezer all
that time and i'm quite excited to
see what it looks like so i'm just going
to take the top off
chocolate looks good
what does the chocolate top sounds like
now only i tried to get a natural tub of
this from the supermarket but
the only flavors available at the moment
i mean uk's still on lockdown
i wear chocolate fred brownie and fish
food
and cookie dough um so i couldn't get
another one to compare it to but
how does he i mean listen to that
that's a chocolate top that's what you
want you wouldn't you want it too hard
you don't
rock solid but it needs to be hard
enough to give you a good kind of crunch
so i think we just need to
dig some pot let's go
[Music]
i mean one thing that instantly comes to
mind is
that this is made with the ben and
jerry's sweet cream base number one
in their recipe book it's quite light
and i don't usually use this
i like my ice cream's quite noise i like
my ice creams a bit more denser
like me so it was a bit of a shock
making this one like i said i'm not
saying it's bad
i'm saying that me personally i would
prefer
a slightly denser ice cream and that's
what you get when you buy
ben and joe's ice cream from the shops
you don't get this kind of base so what
are they giving that to you in their
recipe book i don't know
but what is it what's it taste like
it does taste good it tastes very creamy
the texture is good just a little bit
light for me but the texture is
still soft it's got a good mouth feel if
you will
nice lovely brownies obviously homemade
brownies nice brownies the caramel sauce
judes that tastes really good as well
i mean you like i said you do need that
substantial chocolate top
because in the actual ben jerry's one
when you crack through that
chocolate it just all disintegrates it's
a wafer thin layer
but at least if you make this yourself
you can make it as thick or as thin as
you want it and with whatever chocolate
you want as well
and something else i just wanted to
mention as well is when you make
this chocolate top and it's for all of
those kind of cracker tops that you can
use on ice cream
i use this coconut oil because that's
what we had in the cupboard
but this is the flavored version i
actually don't get the flavour through
because i've used a 70 chocolate so it's
the chocolate it's got enough flavor to
actually mask it but if you do
use this method use try use a flavorless
coconut oil because then you won't get
any of that interfere with the actual
chocolate taste
i hope you enjoy making this one
and please do take some pictures and
send them to us so we can see
what your creations are like but that's
it for this one next week
is it's a nutella special because it's i
think it's international nutella day
so we're going to try and do something a
bit ice creamy with that
but uh thanks for watching this video
and we'll see you next time take care